（ナルト）よいしょっと。
There we go.
よし。
All right!
((フカサク：蔵入り　オーケーじゃ！
Okay, storage complete!
これから木ノ葉へ
ナルトちゃんを戻すけんの。
I'm taking you back to
Hidden Leaf Village!
(そしたら　まずは
タコ探しじゃ))
After that, we'll have to
look for the octopus.
Just like Giant Gramps Sage predicted,
《デカじいちゃん仙人が
予言したとおり→
俺は　タコを探し出し→
I'm going to look for an octopus
九尾の力をコントロールできるように
修業する》
and train to control
the Nine Tails' power.
《そして　もう一度　サスケと会って》
And I'll meet Sasuke once more.
（ヤマト）それじゃ…。
Okay, let's…
（ガイ）さあ　若人よ
いざ　出発だ！
Now, young man…
Time to go!
The Young Man and the Sea
ああ　海だよ　海だよ！
Wow! Look, it's the sea!
ヤッホー　海はいいな！
Yahoo! The sea is great!
（アオバ）あれが
火の国　随一の港です。
That is the Land of Fire's only port.
あそこから雷の国
雲隠れへと出航します。
From there, we'll depart for
the Hidden Cloud Village
in the Land of Lightning.
なあなあ
綱手のばあちゃんが言ってた→
Say… What's this top-secret mission
that Granny Tsunade mentioned?
極秘任務って　いったい何？
秘密だから
極秘任務っていうんだよ　ナルト。
It's called a top-secret mission
because it's a secret, Naruto.
んだよ～！
そんなこと言わずにさぁ→
Oh, come on! Don't say that.
教えてくれてもいいだろ？
You can tell me.
I’ll explain later.
まっ　おいおいね。
ちぇ～！
《まだ　ナルトをごまかす
任務の内容を→
I guess he still hasn’t come up
with a cover story to fool Naruto.
思いついていないのか…》
（シズネ）綱手様　なぜ
こんな大切な時期のナルトに→
Lady Tsunade, why did you assign
Naruto on an S-rank mission
at such a critical time?
Ｓ級任務を？
Not only that, you sent him to
the Land of Lightning by sea.
しかも　海路を使って
雷の国に向かわせるなんて。
（トントン）ブヒ！
（綱手）うむ。
Yes… The Akatsuki is targeting Naruto.
ナルトは　暁に狙われている。
複雑な海路を使うことで→
I chose a difficult sea
voyage on purpose
敵に　その居場所を
悟られないことが→
in order to prevent
the enemy from finding him.
本当の目的だ。
What will Naruto be doing
雷の国　雲隠れの里で
ナルトは　どんなことを？
in Hidden Cloud Village
in the Land of Lightning?
そこは　雷影に任せてある。
I'm leaving that up to Raikage.
すっげえ！
Wow!
立派な帆船が
用意できてんじゃん！
That's a grand sailing ship
you readied for us!
いえ　我々　木ノ葉の帆船は
その隣の…。
Actually… Our Hidden Leaf ship
is the one next to it.
あちらの船なんです。
うん？
That one over there.
けぇ～　しょっぼ～。
Aw man, it looks so shabby.
極秘の任務だからね
大きい船だと目立つだろ？
It's a top-secret mission.
A big ship would attract attention, right?
こういう船で島伝いに
行ったほうがいいんだよ。
It's better to go to the island
on a boat like this.
船乗りたちの姿が
見えないようだが。
I don't see any of the seamen.
実は　外海に出ることを
嫌がってまして。
About that… They refused to set
sail into the open sea.
なに！？　お前ら→
What? Don't tell me you were
stingy on the pay?!
船乗りたちの賃金でも
ケチったのか？
No, it's not that.
いえ　そうではなく。
その…。
なんだ？
Well…
Tell me. I won't get upset.
怒らんから
ちゃんと言ってみろ。
この港の出口にバケモノがいて→
Well, they say there is a monster
out there
外海に出ようとする船を
襲うというのです。
that attacks any boat
that tries to set sail.
バケモノ？
A monster?
《あ～ぁ　貧乏クジ引いたな…》
Oh, boy… Looks like I drew
the short end of the stick.
I don't know what's going to appear,
but I'll crush it to bits!
何が出るかは知らんが→
そんなヤツ　この俺が
ギッタギタにしてやるさ！
ハッハッハッハッハー！
ガイさん
バケモノの正体もわからないのに→
I don’t know if it was a good idea for
Guy to make such a promise.
安請け合いして大丈夫かな？
We don’t even know what
kind of monster it is.
きっと　大丈夫だってばよ！
ほら！
I’m sure he’ll be fine.
See? He looks so eager
doing warm-up exercises!
あんなに元気そうに
準備運動してるし！
大丈夫ですか　ガイさん？
な　なんのこれしき…。
Are you all right, Guy?
Th-This is nothing.
船が
こんなに揺れるものとはな…。
I didn't know the boat
would sway so much.
ちょっと　胃が
驚いてしまっただけだ。
My stomach is a little shocked,
that’s all.
そんなんで
バケモノを倒せるんですか？
How can you crush a monster
in that condition?
Sure I can! I may not look it,
なに！　こう見えて
俺は　本番に強い！　うっ！
but when the time comes,
I'll be strong.
もう　外海なんですが…。
We're in open sea.
何も現れんじゃないか。
I don't see anything.
バケモノめ！
Damn monster!
Did it get scared
and run away after seeing me,
木ノ葉の燃える旋風を恐れて
逃げおったか！
the Leaf’s Burning Hurricane?
（ガイ）バケモノ！
A monster!
なんだ？　あの剣は？
Is that a sword?
口寄せ獣の一種！？
A type of Summoning Animal?
But I don’t sense any jutsu user.
しかし　術者の気配など
どこにもない。
野良の口寄せ獣だというのか？
Could it be a Wild Summoning Animal?
戻ってきたぞ！　避けろ！
It’s coming back! Avoid it!
There's not enough time!
間に合いません！
手を出すな　アオバ！
俺が止める！
Stay back, Aoba!
I'll stop it!
ガイさん！　後ろです！
なに！？
Guy, behind you!
What?!
うわぁ～っ！
♪～
I won't make it!
間に合わない！
I got you! Damn monster!
（ユウスケ）討ち取ったぜ！
このバケモノめ！
うわぁ～！
ムチャすんじゃねえぜ！
兄ちゃん！
Don't be so reckless, pal.
俺の名は　ユウスケだ。
My name is Yusuke!
海面に立つなんて
何者だ？　おめえ！
Who the hell are you and how can
you stand on the ocean surface?!
I'm Naruto, a ninja from
the Hidden Leaf.
俺は　木ノ葉の忍　うずまきナルト！
あとは　俺に任せとけ！
Leave the rest to me!
ん？　あっ！　印が組めねえ！
I can't weave
my signs like this!
えぇ～っ！！
木遁　大樹林の術！
Wood Style: Giant Forest!
♪～
You have to undo your jutsu
or you'll be drawn in!
術を解かねえと
引き込まれちまう！
Quickly, take him and go!
早く！
その人と逃げるんだ！
散千烏の術！
Scattering Crow Jutsu!
♪～
BIG CATCH
口寄せ獣が→
Why would there be
a Summoning Animal in a spot like that?
なんで　あんなところに
いるんだってばよ？
第三次忍界大戦の
生き残りじゃないだろうか。
Maybe it survived
the Third Great Ninja War?
あれでは船乗りたちが恐れるのも
無理ないね。
No wonder the seamen are scared.
アイツは　１５年程前から→
That thing's been living there
for about 15 years.
あそこに　棲みついてやがる。
やはり。
I see.
普通　契約した忍が死ぬと
自分の世界へ戻るものだが。
Normally, when the ninja who
is contracted with it dies,
the animal returns to its own world.
けど　アイツってば
なんで暴れてるんだ？
But why is that one acting up like that?
あの口寄せ獣のなかでは→
Maybe the war has not ended
for that Summoning Animal.
まだ戦いが続いているのかも
しれない。
えぇ。
Yeah.
フンッ　忍同士の戦いなんて
迷惑だぜ。
Your ninja wars are such a nuisance!
アイツのせいで
腰抜け船乗りどもは→
Because of that thing,
all the cowardly seamen refuse
to go to sea anymore!
誰も外海に
出なくなっちまった。
腰抜けって…。
Cowardly?
What were you thinking,
doing something so dangerous?!
あんな危ないことして
兄ちゃん　何　考えてんだよ。
魚を獲るのが
漁師の仕事だからな。
A fisherman's job is to catch fish.
今日という今日は　アイツにトドメを
刺そうと思ってたのに→
I thought I was gonna get rid
of him once and for all,
邪魔しやがってよ。
only to have you interfere!
俺が助けなきゃ
今頃　アイツのエサだろうが。
If I hadn't saved you,
you'd be fish food about now.
フンッ。
アイツは俺たちに任せろ。
You should just leave
that thing to us
もうムチャなことは　やめろってばよ。
and stop acting so recklessly.
うるせぇな！
アイツを倒すのは　このユウスケ様だ。
Shut up.
If anyone beats that thing,
it's gonna be me, Yusuke!
贅沢は言わねえ。
I’m not asking for much.
俺に　あのカジキの体当たりに
負けない→
If I only had a sturdier boat
もう少し頑丈な船がありゃ。
that could withstand that
marlin's body blows.
それに　カジキのパワーに負けねえ
内燃機関がのせてありゃ。
And an internal-combustion engine
to match that marlin's power.
あとは　大物を釣っても折れねえ
ルアー用の釣り竿がありゃ。
And maybe a fishing rod that
has a lure and won't snap.
That's asking for quite a lot.
って　十分　贅沢だろ。
フンッ。
なぁ　どうして　あのカジキに
そこまで　こだわるんだ？
Tell me.
How come you're so determined
to get that marlin?
親父さんか？
Is that your dad?
俺たちは
魚とガチで勝負してんだよ。
We're dead serious about
fighting that fish.
その勝負に
負けちまうようなヤツは→
A guy who'd lose…
親でもなけりゃ　子でもねえ！
isn't worth being called
a father or a son!
ヤマト隊長
なんとかなんねえのかな。
Captain Yamato,
isn't there anything we can do?
なんとかって？
Like what?
Like lending him a hand.
だから　俺たちで
手助けしてやることできねえかな。
I want Yusuke to avenge his dad.
っつうか　ユウスケ兄ちゃんに→
仇を討たせて
やりてぇんだってばよ。
しかし　キミにはＳ級任務が…。
うぉ～っ！
But you have an S-rank mission…
俺は　猛烈に感動したぞ　ヤマト！
I’ve been moved to tears, Yamato!
ここは　ひと肌　脱ごうじゃないか。
Let’s give him a helping hand!
Come on, do it! I’ll do it too!
お前も脱げ　俺も脱ぐぞ！
確かに
あのオバケカジキがいるかぎり→
Well, as long as that monster
is there, we can't set sail.
出航できないしな。
だよな！
あのカジキが口寄せ獣だとしたら→
You see!
If that marlin is
a Summoning Animal,
then we shinobi are to blame
for Yusuke's misfortune.
俺たち忍が　ユウスケ兄ちゃんに
迷惑をかけたことになるし。
それに　あのカジキだって→
And it's not like that marlin
is here because it wants to be.
好きでこの海に
いるわけじゃない。
Okay, okay. I understand.
わかりましたよ　もう。
よ～し！
All right!
BIG CATCH
ユウスケ兄ちゃん！
Yusuke!
竿もあるってばよ！
We have a fishing rod too!
ナルト…。
Naruto…
どうでしょう？
What do you think?
I tried making them
with the data I had available.
資料をもとに
作ってみたんですが。
船も竿も申し分ねえが→
I have no quarrel with
the boat or the rod.
But this is not a motorized boat.
こいつは　手漕ぎ。
カジキのパワーに負けない
内燃機関がついてねえとムリだ。
Without an internal combustion engine
that can match the marlin's power,
it's useless.
それは　この俺に任せておけ。
You can leave that to me!
When it comes to power,
パワーだけなら
この気高き碧い猛獣　マイト・ガイ→
no one can compete with I,
Might Guy, the Noble Blue Beast!
誰にも負けやしない。
So what do you say?
どうだってばよ？
フンッ
余計なことばっかしやがって。
Can't you mind your own business?
こんなに用意されちゃ→
With all this, you're taking
the thrill out of the fight.
アイツとの勝負の醍醐味が
なくなっちまうだろうが。
かぁ…　素直じゃねえな。
Well, aren’t you stubborn?
右前方３０度に　巨大カジキ発見。
Giant marlin spotted 30 degrees
to the right!
おい　ヤツの前方に　まわってくれ。
Hey, go around in front of him!
You got it!
よし　任せておけ！
エイヤッサッサ　エイヤッサ！
前に出たってばよ。
We're up front!
Okay, I'm going to release the lure.
よし　ルアーを流すぞ。
って　何だ　これ！？
Hey, what is that?!
It's a special lure made in proportion
to its huge size.
ヤツの巨体に合わせた　特製ルアーだ。
I meant, why does it look
just like me?
そうじゃなくて…
何で俺そっくり？
お前は派手で
食いつきがよさそうだからな。
You're showy and look like
you'd be good bait.
No! I'm gonna get eaten!
いや～　俺が食われる！
もっと速く！
Faster!
We have to make it think
this lure is nice and fresh!
ヤツに　ルアーが生きのいいエサだと
思わせねえと。
Leave it to me!
任せろ
八門遁甲　第二休門　開！
Eight Inner Gates!
Second Gate, Gate of Rest! Open!
ゲキマユ先生　もっとだ！
Bushy Brow Sensei! Faster!
第四傷門　第五杜門　開！
Fourth Gate, Gate of Pain…
Fifth Gate, Gate of Closing…
Open!
こい　こい　こい！
Come on, come on, come on!
おっ！
ヒット！
Bull's-eye!
アイツ　まんまと
かぶりつきやがった。
He took the bait!
えっ！？
なんか　心が痛い…。
Oh, that hurts my heart.
Say, we have to reel it in quickly.
なあ　早く
引っ張りあげねえのか？
You idiot. If we did that,
the line would snap.
バカ野郎　そんなことしたら
糸がもたねえ。
遊ばせて　ヤツが疲れるのを待つ。
We'll let it play
and wait until it tires out.
We'll run out of line like this!
このままじゃ
糸がなくなっちまうぞ。
I know that.
わかってる
この船ごと引かせる。
Let it pull the boat!
ヤツについていけるか？
Can you keep up with it?
Nothing is impossible for me!
この俺に不可能はない！
うおぉ～！！
もう漕がなくていい。
You don't need to row anymore.
Just follow the marlin’s lead
and steer the boat.
ヤツの動きに合わせて
舵をきってくれ。
ふぅ　助かった
さすがに　もう　限界だった。
Good. I was reaching my limit.
泳げ　泳げ！
力を使い切るんだ。
Swim, swim…
Use up all your strength.
It's got amazing stamina
to swim at this speed.
これほどのスピードで泳ぎ続けるとは
相当なスタミナだ。
だが　振りきろうとする力も
いつか尽きる。
But it will eventually use up
the energy to resist.
Then the real fight begins.
そこからが勝負でしょう。
It's finally showing signs of exhaustion.
ヤツめ　やっと疲れが見えてきたぜ。
くっ！
ユウスケ兄ちゃん！
Yusuke!
Stay out of my way!
邪魔すんじゃねえ！
これは　俺とアイツのガチファイティングだ。
This fight is between him and me!
わかってるってばよ。
I know that!
Here we go.
《もうすぐだ　今度こそ…。
This time... This time for sure.
今度こそ　ヤツを！》
Guess it’s time to help out.
そろそろ助けがいるかな。
手出しちゃダメだ。
Don't help him!
ユウスケ兄ちゃんに　自分の手で
仇を討ってもらうんだ。
Yusuke will get his revenge
with his own two hands.
やれやれ。
任せるしかないみたいだね。
Oh dear…
I guess we have no choice.
All right, just a little more!
よし　もうちょっと！
Give it up already!
観念しやがれ！
こいつ　まだ　こんな力が！
He still has so much strength.
くっ！
まずい！
This isn't good!
Yusuke!
兄ちゃん！
この～っ！
♪～
You avenged your dad.
親父さんの仇　討てたってばよ。
ああ！
Yeah!
Why didn't that Summoning Animal
return to its birthplace?
あの口寄せ獣　なぜ
生まれ故郷に戻らなかったのか。
我慢しろ　今　抜いてやる。
Easy there. I'll get it out.
これ…。
This is…
It's a Demon Wind Shuriken
from the Hidden Leaf.
木ノ葉の風魔手裏剣だな。
やっぱり　あのカジキも→
So it was a victim of
the Third Great Ninja War, after all.
第三次忍界大戦の
犠牲者だったんだな。
生まれ故郷に
戻してやりたいんだが。
If possible, we'd like to return it
to its birthplace.
ああ　好きにしろ。
一対一の真剣勝負は
もう終わった。
恨みっこなしだ。
♪～
（くもじい）
もしもし　そこのあなた。
たまには　空から日本を眺めてみる
というのは　どうじゃろう？
今回は　渋谷発展の歴史スペシャルじゃ。
（くもみ）渋谷？
なぜ渋谷が流行の発信地に
なったのか。
えっ　理由があるんですか？
あの１０９も昔は…。
小さなお店がぎっしり！
そして　渋谷の未来も見ていくぞ。
おぉ～！